So, I teach college students about inequality and race in education,
إذا، أنا أدرس طلاب الجامعة عن عدم المساواة والعرق في التعليم،
and I like to leave my office open to any of my students
وأحب ترك باب مكتبي مفتوحا لأي من طلابي
who might just want to see me to chat.
الذين قد يريدون فقط رؤيتي للدردشة معي.
And a few semesters ago,
وقبل بضعة فصول دراسية،
one of my more cheerful students, Mahari,
واحد من أمرح طلابي، مهاري،
actually came to see me
جاء لرؤيتي
and mentioned that he was feeling a bit like an outcast because he's black.
وأشار إلى أنه يشعر قليلا بأنه دخيل لكونه أسود.
He had just transferred to NYU from a community college
مهاري قد انتقل مؤخرا إلى جامعة نيويورك من كلية مجتمع
on a merit scholarship,
في منحة تميز.
and turns out,
واتضح أن
only about five percent of students at NYU are black.
حوالي 5% فقط من الطلاب في جامعة نيويورك من السود.
And so I started to remember
وبدأت بالتذكر
that I know that feeling of being an outsider
أنني أعرف ذلك الشعور أن تكون دخيلا
in your own community.
في مجتمعك.
It's partially what drew me to my work.
إنه جزئيًا ما دفعني لعملي.
At my university,
في جامعتي،
I'm one of the few faculty members of color,
أنا واحد من الأقلية الملونين من أعضاء هيئة التدريس.
and growing up, I experienced my family's social mobility,
وفي مرحلة النمو، شهدت الحراك الاجتماعي لأسرتي،
moving out of apartments into a nice house,
والانتقال من الشقق إلى منزل جميل،
but in an overwhelmingly white neighborhood.
ولكن إلى حي بأغلبية بيض ساحقة.
I was 12,
كنت في الثانية عشر،
and kids would say that were surprised that I didn't smell like curry.
وكان الأطفال يقولون أنه من المفاجئ أن رائحتي ليست كالكاري.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That's because school is in the morning,
ذلك لأن المدرسة في الصباح
and I had Eggo waffles for breakfast.
وكنت أفطر وافل ايقو
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Curry is for dinner.
الكاري للعشاء.
So when Mahari was leaving,
وعندما كان مهاري يخرج،
I asked him how he was coping with feeling isolated.
سألته كيف كان يتأقلم مع الشعور بالانعزال.
And he said that despite feeling lonely,
رد قائلًا بالرغم من الشعور بالوحدة،
he just threw himself at his work,
كان يلقي نفسه في عمله فقط،
that he built strategies around his grit
وبنى استراتيجيات حول مثابرته
and his desire to be successful.
ورغبته بأن يكون ناجحا.
A mentor of mine is actually Dr. Angela Duckworth,
مستشار لي في الواقع هي الطبيبة أنجيلا دوكورث،
the psychologist at UPenn who has defined this stick-to-itiveness of grit
العالمة النفسانية في UPenn التي فسرت التمسك بالإصرار والمثابرة
as being "the perseverance and passion for long-term goals."
بكونه "المثابرة والشغف لتحقيق أهداف طويلة الأجل."
Angela's book has become a bestseller,
كتاب أنجيلا أصبح من أفضل الكتب مبيعًا،
and schools across the country,
والمدارس في جميع أنحاء البلاد،
particularly charter schools,
ولاسيما المدارس المستقلة،
have become interested in citing "grit" as a core value.
أصبحت مهتمة في الاستشهاد ب " المثابرة" كقيمة أساسية.
But sometimes grit isn't enough,
ولكن بعض الأحيان المثابرة ليست كافية،
especially in education.
خصوصًا في التعليم.
So when Mahari was leaving my office,
لذا عندما كان مهاري يغادر مكتبي،
I worried that he might need something more specific
قلقت من أنه قد يحتاج إلى أمر أكثر تحديدا
to combat the challenges that he mentioned to me.
لمكافحة التحديات التي أشار إليها
As a sociologist, I also study achievement,
كعالم اجتماع أدرس أيضًا الانجاز،
but from a slightly different perspective.
ولكن من منظور مختلف قليلًا.
I research students who have overcome immense obstacles
أبحث في الطلاب الذين تغلبوا على عقبات هائلة
related to their background.
أرتباطًا بخلفياتهم.
Students from low-income,
الطلاب ذوي الدخل المنخفض،
often single-parent households,
وغابًا ماتكون أسر بوالد واحد،
students who have been homeless, incarcerated or perhaps undocumented,
الطلاب الذين كانوا بلا مأوى، مسجونين أو ربما غير موثقين،
or some who have struggled with substance abuse
وبعض الذين عانوا من تعاطي المخدرات،
or lived through violent or sexual trauma.
أو عاشوا صدمات عنيفة أو جنسية.
So let me tell you about two of the grittiest people I've met.
لذا دعوني أخبركم عن اثنين من أعظم الأشخاص الذين قابلتهم.
Tyrique was raised by a single mother,
تايريك ربته أم عزباء.
and then after high school, he fell in with the wrong crowd.
وبعد الثانوية وقع في الحشد الخاطئ.
He got arrested for armed robbery.
تم اعتقاله في سطو مسلح.
But in prison, he started to work hard.
ولكن في السجن بدأ بالعمل الجاد.
He took college credit courses,
حصل على دورات جامعية،
so when he got out, he was able to get a master's,
لذا عندما خرج كان قادرًا على الحصول على درجة الماجستير.
and today he's a manager at a nonprofit.
واليوم هو مدير في منظمة غير ربحية.
Vanessa had to move around a lot as a kid,
فانيسا كان عليها الانتقال كثيرًا كطفلة،
from the Lower East Side to Staten Island to the Bronx.
من الجانب الشرقي السفلى إلى جزيرة ستاتن إلى برونكس.
She was raised primarily by her extended family,
نشأت من قبل عشيرتها،
because her own mother had a heroin addiction.
لأن والدتها كانت مدمنة هروين.
Yet at 15,
في ال15 من العمر،
Vanessa had to drop out of school,
كان على فينيسا الخروج من المدرسة،
and she had a son of her own.
وقد أصبحت أماً،
But eventually, she was able to go to community college,
ولكنها في النهاية، كانت قادرة على الذهاب لكلية المجتمع
get her associate's,
حصلت على الزمالة،
then go to an elite college to finish her bachelor's.
وانتقلت إلى كلية نخبة لإنهاء البكالوريوس.
So some people might hear these stories and say,
بعض الأشخاص قد يستمع لهذه القصص ويقول،
"Yes, those two definitely have grit.
"أجل، هذان بالتأكيد لديهما العزم.
They basically pulled themselves up by the bootstraps."
هما فعليا قد رفعا أنفسهما بدون مساعدة أحد ."
But that's an incomplete picture,
ولكن هذه صورة غير كاملة،
because what's more important
لأن الأكثر أهمية
is that they had factors in their lives that helped to influence their agency,
هو أنه لديهم عوامل في حياتهم ساعدت في التأثير على قوتهم،
or their specific capacity
أو قدراتهم الخاصة
to actually overcome the obstacles that they were facing
ليتغلبوا على العقبات التي واجهوها
and navigate the system given their circumstances.
واجتياز النظام بالنظر إلى ظروفهم.
So, allow me to elaborate.
دعوني أوضح لكم،
In prison, Tyrique was actually aimless at first,
في السجن تايرك كان في البداية بلا هدف،
as a 22-year-old on Rikers Island.
كشاب ف ال22 من العمر في جزيرة ريكرز.
This is until an older detainee took him aside
ذلك حتى أخذه سجين أكبر جانبًا
and asked him to help with the youth program.
وطلب منه المساعدة في برنامج الشباب.
And in mentoring youth,
وفي توجيه الشباب،
he started to see his own mistakes and possibilities in the teens.
بدأ برؤية أخطائه والإمكانات في المراهقين.
This is what got him interested in taking college-credit courses.
ذلك ما دفعه لأخذ دورات جامعية مدفوعة.
And when he got out,
وعندما خرج من السجن،
he got a job with Fortune Society,
حصل على عمل في "ثروة المجتمع"
where many executives are people who have been formerly incarcerated.
حيث العديد من موظفي الإدارة قد سُجِنوا سابقًا.
So then he was able to get a master's in social work,
فكان قادرًا على الحصول على الماجستير في العمل الاجتماعي،
and today, he even lectures at Columbia about prison reform.
واليوم يحاضر في كولومبيا عن تحسين السجن.
And Vanessa ...
فنيسا...
well, after the birth of her son,
بعد ولادة ابنها،
she happened to find a program called Vocational Foundation
عثرت على برنامج يدعى مؤسسة مهنية،
that gave her 20 dollars biweekly,
يعطيها 20$ أسبوعيًا،
a MetroCard
بطاقة مترو
and her first experiences with a computer.
وتجربتها الأولى مع الكمبيوتر.
These simple resources are what helped her get her GED,
هذه المصادر البسيطة هي ما أعانها على الحصول على شهادة GED ,
but then she suffered from a very serious kidney failure,
ولكنها بعد ذلك قد عانت من فشل كلوي حاد،
which was particularly problematic because she was only born with one kidney.
وهي مشكلة خاصة لأنها وُلدت بكلية واحدة.
She spent 10 years on dialysis waiting for a successful transplant.
قضت 10 أعوام معتمدة على غسيل الكلى تنتظر عملية نقل ناجحة.
After that,
بعد ذلك،
her mentors at community college had kept in touch with her,
مرشدها في كلية المجتمع بقي على تواصل معها،
and so she was able to go,
وذلك مكنّها من المضي قدما،
and they put her in an honors program.
ووضعوها في برنامج الشرف.
And that's the pathway that allowed her to become accepted
وذلك هو الطريق الذي سمح لها بأن تُقبل
to one of the most elite colleges for women in the country,
في واحدة من أكثر الكليات نخبة للنساء في الدولة،
and she received her bachelor's at 36,
وحصل على شهادة البكالوريوس في عامها ال36
setting an incredible example for her young son.
واضعة مثالًا مذهل لولدها اليافع.
What these stories primarily indicate is that teaching is social
الذي تشير إليه هذه القصص بشكل رئيسي هو أن التعليم اجتماعي
and benefits from social scaffolding.
ويستفيد من السقالات الاجتماعية.
There were factors pushing these two in one direction,
كانت هناك عوامل تدفع هذين الاثنين إلى طريق واحد،
but through tailored mentorship and opportunities,
ولكن من خلال فرص وإرشادات مصمة،
they were able to reflect on their circumstances
تمكنوا من التغلب على ظروفهم
and resist negative influences.
ومقاومة التأثيرات السلبية.
They also learned simple skills like developing a network,
تعلموا أيضًا مهارات بسيطة مثل تطوير شبكة،
or asking for help --
أو طلب المساعدة --
things many of us in this room can forget that we have needed from time to time,
أشياء الكثير منّا في هذه الغرفة قد نسي أننا قد نحتاجها من وقت لآخر،
or can take for granted.
أو يمكنه أخذها كهبة.
And when we think of people like this,
وعندما نفكر في الأشخاص هكذا،
we should only think of them as exceptional, but not as exceptions.
يجب أن نفكر فيهم باعتبارهم استثنائيين وليس كاستثناء.
Thinking of them as exceptions absolves us
التفكير فيهم كاستثناء يعفينا
of the collective responsibility to help students in similar situations.
من تحمل المسؤولية الاجتماعية لمساعدة الطلاب في مواقف مشابهة.
When Presidents Bush, Obama and now even Trump,
عندما دعا الرئيس بوش و أوباما وحتى ترمب
have called education "the civil rights issue of our time,"
التعليم بأنه " قضية الحقوق المدنية في عصرنا. "
perhaps we should treat it that way.
ربما يجب أن نعامله بتلك الطريقة.
If schools were able to think about the agency that their students have
إذا استطاعت المدارس التفكير بالقوات الكامنة في طلابها
and bring to the table when they push them,
ووضعها أمامهم عندما يدفعونهم
what students learn can become more relevant to their lives,
ما يتعلمه الطلاب يمكن أن يصبح مرتبطًا أكثر بحياتهم،
and then they can tap into those internal reservoirs of grit and character.
ومن ثم يمكنهم الاعتماد على الخزائن الداخلية من العزم والشخصية.
So this here --
هذا هنا -
My student Mahari
هو طالبي "مهاري"
got accepted to law school with scholarships,
قُبل في كلية الحقوق بمنحة دراسية،
and not to brag,
ليس للتباهي
but I did write one of his letters of recommendation.
ولكنني قد كتبت واحدة من رسائل التوصية خاصته.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And even though I know hard work is what got him this achievement,
وبالرغم من علمي بأن العمل الجاد هو ما أوصله لهذا الإنجاز،
I've seen him find his voice along the way,
قد رأيته وهو يحصل على صوته طيلة الطريق،
which as someone who's grown up a little bit shy and awkward,
وهو كشخص قد نمى بالقليل من الخجل والإحراج،
I know it takes time and support.
أعرف أنه يحتاج للوقت والدعم.
So even though he will rely a lot on his grit
لذا بالرغم من كونه سيعتمد كثيرًا على عزمه
to get him through that first-year law school grind,
لعبور اضهاد السنة الأولى في كلية القانون،
I'll be there as a mentor for him,
سأكون هناك كمرشد له،
check in with him from time to time,
أتفحصه من وقت لآخر،
maybe take him out to get some curry ...
ربما نخرج سويا للحصول على بعض الكاري ...
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
so that he can keep growing his agency to succeed even more.
ليتمكن من زيادة قوته لنجاح أكبر.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)